<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://velythyl.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://velythyl.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-11-26T02:43:18+00:00</updated><id>https://velythyl.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Charlie Gauthier&apos;s personal website </subtitle><entry><title type="html">IVADO//Scientist in residence//Acrylic Robotics</title><link href="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/acrylic-robotics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IVADO//Scientist in residence//Acrylic Robotics"/><published>2022-11-07T15:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-07T15:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/acrylic-robotics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/acrylic-robotics/"><![CDATA[<p>During the summer of 2022, I participated in <a href="https://ivado.ca/en/scientist-in-residence/">IVADO’s Scientist in Residence</a> program (which debuted that very same year). This program entailed matching graduate students to startups, where the startups would benefit from a knowledge transfer from the student.</p> <p>I was paired with <a href="https://acrylicrobotics.ca/">Acrylic Robotics</a>, an art-tech startup. The goal of Acrylic Robotics is to democratize art, allowing up-and-coming artists to duplicate their pieces in order to reach a much, much wider potential market. To survive from art, one must normally go through the gallery system, where curated pieces sell for large sums of money. New artists are normally not welcome, and even when they are, they cannot viably live from their art: because they are new to the art world, the galleries set their pieces’ prices to relatively low amounts. Thanks to Acrylic Robotics, these new artists will be able to sell the same art piece many times. This will help them survive from solely making art and widen their reach to new art enjoyers.</p> <p>During my time in the Scientist in Residence program, I helped shape Acrylic Robotics’ direction by giving insights into the world of Deep Learning.</p> <p>Here’s a cool video of the <a href="https://www.mecademic.com/en/meca500-robot-arm">Mecademic 500</a> painting a piece using Acrylic Robotics’ technology.</p> <iframe src="https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?height=315&amp;href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Facrylicrobotics%2Fvideos%2F554832089607603%2F&amp;show_text=false&amp;width=560&amp;t=0" width="560" height="315" style="border:none;overflow:hidden" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share"> </iframe> <p><em>Video source: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/acrylicrobotics/">Acrylic Robotics’ Facebook page</a></em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="art"/><category term="manipulation"/><category term="robot-arm"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Painting reproduction using real paint and artificial arms]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IVADO//Octobre Numérique</title><link href="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/octobre-numerique/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IVADO//Octobre Numérique"/><published>2022-10-27T11:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-27T11:20:00+00:00</updated><id>https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/octobre-numerique</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/octobre-numerique/"><![CDATA[<p>I was invited to present at <a href="https://ivado.ca/en/events/ivado-digital-october-2022/">IVADO’s Digital Octobre event</a>.</p> <p>This event was shock-full of the new generation of researchers in the Comp. Sci., Psychology, Medical, Biologogy and Physics/Astrophysics fields in Montreal. All of the invited speakers worked with ML as part of the research they presented at the event. Super cool to see!</p> <p>I presented a subset of my master’s thesis during a 15 minute presentation. The goal was to vulgarize my research as much as possible. This work hasn’t been published yet, so I can’t really go into much details, but I can say that it deals with robustifying reinforcement learning for quadruped robots. You can look at <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1WseemCwGYg1pdZx7lHDFR5czjfosMkSFxXDEUTMup0U/edit?usp=sharing">my slides</a> if you are really curious.</p> <p>My presentation was judged first place for my category and, thanks to <a href="https://www.vidensanalytics.com/">Videns Analytics</a>, I was awarded a 1000$ prize! <img style="display:inline; height:2em;" src="/assets/img/emojis/60fps_parrot.gif"/></p> <p><img src="/assets/img/ivado_octobre_numerique/image_720.png" style="max-width:100%"/></p> <p><em>Photo of me presenting during the event. Image source: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ivado.qc">IVADO’s Facebook page</a></em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="vulgarization"/><category term="conference"/><category term="quadrupeds"/><category term="rl"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was invited to present at IVADO’s Digital Octobre event.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mila//Robotics Summer School</title><link href="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/mila-summer-school/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mila//Robotics Summer School"/><published>2022-10-07T23:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-07T23:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/mila-summer-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/mila-summer-school/"><![CDATA[<p>I had the pleasure of participating in the 2022 Mila Robotics Summer School. Lots of great speakers, nice students, and great talks.</p> <p>Over three days, we developed a control policy for a robot dog. We then rolled it out quite a few times, trying to fine tune it. On the final day, we had a competition: who can reach a designated goal while avoiding a foam obstacle?</p> <p>Well. I wish I could say we did well, but our robot just sort of… died… the day of the competition.</p> <p><img src="https://mila.quebec/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/IMG_0586-scaled.jpg" style="max-width:100%"/></p> <p><em>Photo of the good robot, with the very dead robot in the background, to the left of the image. Image source: <a href="https://mila.quebec/en/mila-robotics-summer-school/">https://mila.quebec/en/mila-robotics-summer-school/</a></em></p> <p>Still, this was an incredible experience and I strongly recommend next year’s edition to anyone interested in learning for robotics! You don’t need to be an ML expert, robotics monkey, or math genius :)</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="quadrupeds"/><category term="rl"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had the pleasure of participating in the 2022 Mila Robotics Summer School. Lots of great speakers, nice students, and great talks.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ICLR//Blog Track 2022</title><link href="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/iclr-bt-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ICLR//Blog Track 2022"/><published>2022-10-06T14:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-06T14:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/iclr-bt-2022</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://velythyl.github.io/blog/2022/iclr-bt-2022/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>You can see the full website <a href="https://iclr-blog-track.github.io/home">here</a></strong></p> <div class="jekyll-twitter-plugin"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">ICLR is happy to announce the call for contributions for our very first &quot;Blog Posts Track&quot;. We invite submissions in blog format discussing previously published papers at ICLR. For details on this exciting new experiment in publication models see: <a href="https://t.co/L0M11HLzhC">https://t.co/L0M11HLzhC</a></p>&mdash; ICLR 2025 (@iclr_conf) <a href="https://twitter.com/iclr_conf/status/1437460881047175169?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 13, 2021</a></blockquote> <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> </div> <p>This project was sparked by a conversation I had with the professor of my Game Theory &amp; Machine Learning class, <a href="https://gauthiergidel.github.io/">Gauthier Gidel</a> and with a friend and student in the class, <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/daviddobre/?originalSubdomain=ca">David Dobre</a>. We were both feeling frustrated with the amount of glaring results cherry-picking in machine learning papers, and about how incremental results get completely discarded as useless, even if they offer important new research insights. Our solution was to incentivize research blog posts. By giving a dedicated venue for incremental results, test-of-time works, and other valuable-but-not-pivotal contributions, we hoped to reduce their inclusion at other venues. By removing incremental results from bigger conferences, we hoped to reduce the cherry-picking that was often “required” to have fully “groundbreaking” results.</p> <p>To do so, we wanted blog posts to be formally recognized as scientific achievements. We contacted <a href="http://sbubeck.com/">Sebastien Bubeck</a> (Sr. Principal Research Manager at Microsoft) and <a href="https://www.cvernade.com/">Claire Vernade</a> (former Research Scientist at DeepMind, now Group Leader at University of Tuebingen). Together, we wrote a proposal to <a href="https://iclr.cc/">ICLR</a> proposing they let us organise a new conference track, the Blog Track. They accepted, and we became inaugural track chairs. Being track chair at such a huge conference at 24 years of age was an extraordinary experience.</p> <p>Even though it was the first edition of a proper blog track for our field, it was a resounding success. As inaugural track chairs, we accepted 20 posts out of 61, roughly the size of the first ICLR conference (which is now one of the big ML conferences). Social media was abuzz about this track, with overwhelmingly positive feedback.</p> <div class="jekyll-twitter-plugin"><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We (<a href="https://twitter.com/gauthier_gidel?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@gauthier_gidel</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/velythyl?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@velythyl</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/busycalibrating?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@busycalibrating</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/vernadec?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@vernadec</a> &amp; myself) would like to announce the accepted blog posts to <a href="https://twitter.com/iclr_conf?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@iclr_conf</a>&#39;s 1st Blogpost Track. Experiment was a great success with 20 accepted posts out of 61 submissions, roughly the size of the 1st <a href="https://twitter.com/iclr_conf?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@iclr_conf</a> itself! 1/24</p>&mdash; Sebastien Bubeck (@SebastienBubeck) <a href="https://twitter.com/SebastienBubeck/status/1516789239702196224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 20, 2022</a></blockquote> <script async="" src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> </div> <p>Being indirectly talked about in a Reddit thread with 200 upvotes in the ML subreddit was also a bit of a weird experience!</p> <iframe id="reddit-embed" src="https://www.redditmedia.com/r/MachineLearning/comments/pntwi6/n_iclr_2022_announced_a_call_for_contributions/?ref_source=embed&amp;ref=share&amp;embed=true&amp;theme=dark" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin allow-popups" style="border: none;" height="431" width="640" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="vulgarization"/><category term="conference"/><category term="iclr"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blog posts as conference publications]]></summary></entry></feed>